Guide to the Paul Horgan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Early Acquisitions, 1922-1980; 49.32; (124 Boxes)
  - Oversize
    - Artwork
      - Drawings for Great River
        - Rio Grande gorge at Arroyo Hondo, New Mexico, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande in Southern Colorado, undated (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Confluence of West and South forks, Rio Grande in Colorado, 1947 (Box 114 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at Alamesa, Colorado, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Wagon Wheel Gap, Colorado, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - First Capitol, Republic of the Rio Grande, Laredo, 1945 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Young Spanish Courtier, after Sanchez Coello, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Church of Islet del Sur and Socorro del Sur, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Cordova, Mosque doorway, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Painted pebble, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Firedrill and Hearth, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Bone awl or dagger, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Spanish Colonial Candle Holder, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Ruins of Ft. Craig, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Valverde Mesa, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande faces, women, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Spanish sword, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Bust of Phillip II by Lemi, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Spanish faces, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at Presidio, Texas, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Spanish spur, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Juarez, 1951 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Franklin Mountains, El Paso, Texas, 1951 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Boca Chica, Texas, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Bather, El Paso, Juarez, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Child's mummy- Big Band Cave Culture, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Uniform dress coat, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Chapel at Mier, Tamaulipas, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Spanish Stirrup, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande near Las Cruces, New Mexico, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Mexican pottery, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Bulfo, Tome, New Mexico, 1951 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Sand dunes in Mexico, across RIo Grande at El Paso, Texas, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Eagle Pass, looking north, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Rio Grande at Presidio, Texas, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Flora, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Approaching Presidio, Texas, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Stage coach interior, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Palms at Weslaco, Texas, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Railroad yards, Franklin Mountains, El Paso, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Store at Roma, Texas, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Lighthouse, Port Isabel, Texas, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Mouth of Santa Elena Canyon, Big Bend, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - El Paso and Mt. Franklin, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - North of El Paso, Bend in the river, 1947 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Bell tower, San Juan Capistrano, San Antonio, Texas, 1949 (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Creede, Colorado, undated (Box 115 (Oversize))
        - Old Bridge at Otowi, New Mexico, undated (Box 116 (Oversize))
        - South of Las Cruces, undated (Box 116 (Oversize))
        - Field studies, undated (Box 116 (Oversize))
      - Scenes of Mexico
        - Parral, 1962 (Box 117 (Oversize))
        - Mexico Cathedral, 1962 (Box 117 (Oversize))
        - Camargo, undated (Box 117 (Oversize))
        - Chihuahua, undated (Box 117 (Oversize))
        - San Juan de Dios, Mexico, 1962 (Box 117 (Oversize))
        - Durango, 1962 (Box 117 (Oversize))
        - Cathedral of Durango, 1962 (Box 117 (Oversize))
      - Drawings for Lamy of Santa Fe
        - De Vargas Hotel, Santa Fe, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - Santa Fe, 1883, St. Michael's College, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - 1870's military headquarters store, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - Governor's Palace, 1850s, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - Sitting in Front of La Fonda, Santa Fe, 1859, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - Tucumcari Mission, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - [Gua?] Church and Bay, 1967 (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - S2 Fire Co./ Chemical No. I, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - Gas street light, S.F., 1882, undated (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - Ingalls Crossing, Arkansas River, 1967 (Box 118 (Oversize))
        - XXth Century Church at Conejos, Colorado, undated (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - Plaza, Alamos, Mexico, undated (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - Black leather travelling bag of Archbishop Lamy, undated (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - Cruets of Lamy, Loretto Chapel, Santa Fe, 1968 (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - Lamy's Lavabo pitcher and basin, Loretto Chapel, 1968 (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - Ohio River at Cincinnati, 1967 (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - At Central City, Colorado, undated (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - Santa Ana, Son., 1967 (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - San Francisco Xavier del Bac, 1967 (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - [Alain?], 1967 (Box 119 (Oversize))
        - Bishop's Lodge, Palm Sunday, 1965 (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - St. Louis Cathedral, New Orleans, 1967 (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - U.S. Army Soldiers in Santa Fe Plaza, undated (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - Bandstand, Santa Fe Plaza, 1882, undated (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - San Felipe de Neri, Albuquerque, undated (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - Chapel of Our Lady of Light, Loretto Convent, Santa Fe, undated (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - Archbishop Lamy's Horsehair Trunk, 1968 (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - Archbishop Lamy's Ciborium, undated (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - Notre Dame de Bonne Nouvelle, undated (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - Palace of Governors, Santa Fe, 1882, undated (Box 120 (Oversize))
        - La Fonda, Santa Fe, 1882, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Citizens' dress, 1859, Santa Fe, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Regimental Bandsman, Santa Fe, 1882, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Cathedral tower, Alamos, Mexico, 1967 (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - San Francisco St., Santa Fe, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Itinerant Photographer's Gallery, Santa Fe, 1882, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Throne of Archbishop Lamy, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Lamy's Chalice, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Carrying case for the chalice of Lamy, undated (Box 121 (Oversize))
        - Golden, Colorado, undated (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - La Maison Natale de J.B. Lamy, undated (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - Clerment- Ferrand, undated (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - View taken from near Lempdes... taken toward Le Puys-de-Dome and Clermont Ferrand (Cathedral), undated (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - Clermont- Ferrand, 1965 (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - Unidentified drawings, undated; 4 (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - Hidalgo del Parral, undated (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - Cathedral Durango, undated (Box 122 (Oversize))
        - Hidalgo de Parral- the Church, undated (Box 123 (Oversize))
        - Puebla, the Cathedral from the fort,a dusty Sunday, undated (Box 123 (Oversize))
        - Unidentifed drawing, undated; 2 (Box 123 (Oversize))
        - Veracruz, The German Freighter, 1962 (Box 123 (Oversize))
        - Unidentified drawing, undated (Box 123 (Oversize))
        - House of Cortez, undated (Box 123 (Oversize))
        - [Granary gate?], undated (Box 123 (Oversize))
      - Original drawings for The Centuries of Santa Fe, undated (Box 123 (Oversize))
      - Unsorted
        - Labels, undated (Box 124 (Oversize))
        - Religious Procession, San Jancinto St., Santa Fe, undated (Box 124 (Oversize))
        - Incense Burner in form of Rain God, undated (Box 124 (Oversize))
        - Moctezuma's Headdress, undated (Box 124 (Oversize))
      - Paul Horgan portrait by Wyeth, Harriette, charcoal, 1929 (Box 235 (Oversize))
      - Landscape, watercolor, undated (Box 235 (Oversize))
      - Portrait of Eric Knight by Peter Hurd, undated (Box 236 (Art))
- November 1976 Acquisition, 1963-1965, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 585
  - Anthology 10th Grade English Humanities volume III, 1965 (Box 125)
  - The Sun Turtle and the Lantern, undated (Box 125)
  - Expert from A Distant Trumpet, 1963 (Box 125)
  - Epistle from Mr. and Mrs. Richard Wilbur: A Birthday Garland of Clerihew for Mr. Paul Horgan, undated (Box 125)
- December 1977 Acquisition, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 584
  - Lamy of Santa Fe, photographs, undated; 3 (Box 126)
- 1985 Acquisitions, 4.71; (11 boxes)
  - April 1985 Acquisition, 1981, undated
    Former call number: Uncat Za File 93
    - Letters to Paul Horgan from Delacorte, Pantheon, Rinehard & Co., and Ticknor & Fields, undated-1981 (Box 127)
  - May 1985 Acquisition
    Manuscripts, correspondence, photographs and printed material. Includes: Devil in the Desert, BOMC material, Josiah Gregg and His Vision, Notebooks, Whitewater, etc.
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 94
    - "Eugene F. Saxton" for the Dictionary of American Biography. Autograph manuscript and typescript in various states, 1912-1969, undated; 2 (Box 127)
    - Correspondence with publisher regarding Josiah Gregg and his Vision of the Early West, 1978-1979 (Box 127)
    - Josiah Gregg early material; introduction and bibliography note draft, etc., undated; 10 (Box 127)
    - Josiah Gregg galley and page proofs, undated; 6 (Box 127)
    - Return of the Weed, undated; 2 (Box 127)
    - "Rome Eternal", 1958 (Box 127)
    - The Saintmaker's Christmas Eve, original note (autograph manuscript), undated (Box 127)
    - Things as They Are, original notes, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 127)
    - Whitewater, undated; 9 (Box 127)
    - "Testimonial to Paul Horgan by The Catholic Book Club, 1957," typescript, carbon (Box 128)
    - Cripps, Thomans & Culbert David. The Negro Soldier, typescript (photocopy) with manuscript corrections, 1977 (Box 128)
    - BOMC correspondence and miscellaneous typed material, 1969-1970 (Box 128)
    - BOMC book reports, A - Z, undated; 8 (Box 128)
    - Book of the Month Club NEWS: issues containing reviews by Paul Horgan, 1970-1976; 2 (Box 128)
    - BOMC pamphlets about Paul Horgan, undated (Box 128)
    - Papers relating to Paul Horgan's work on the "Constellation Library" project of the National Council on the Humanities, 1966-1989; 5 (Box 128)
    - Letters to Paul Horgan, A - Z, 1957-1976 (Box 128)
    - Correspondence (miscellaneous), 1976, undated (Box 128)
    - The Devil in the Desert, 1976; 1 (Box 220 (Restricted Fragile))
    - The Beethoven Society of Roswell, New Mexico. The surviving archives, 1935-54; programs 1941-1954. Autograph manuscript and typed. 1 volume (Box 128)
    - Photographs, 1903-1977, undated; 34 (Box 128)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 128)
    - Printed material, including articles by or about Paul Horgan; awards and honorary degrees received by Paul Horgan; programs for musical/ theatrical works with scripts/lyrics by Paul Horgan, 1923-1976; 9 (Box 129)
    - Isabel Echols albums of illustrative material (for publication by Paul Horgan), undated; 5 (Box 130)
    - Research photos, undated; 5 (Box 130)
    - "Scrapbook pages" [possibly more Isabel Echols albums of illustrative material, removed from binders?], undated; 8 (Box 130)
    - Pamphlets, 1964, 1979, undated (Box 130)
    - Oversize
      - Two portraits of Paul Horgan, 1946 (Box 131 (Oversize))
      - Two research photographs, undated (Box 131 (Oversize))
  - May 1985 Acquisition, 1930s-1983
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 325
    - Wesleyan Library Notes, 1981 (Box 132)
    - Ten untitled sketches of men, collage, signed, 1980 September 10 (Box 132)
    - Untitled sketch of a ballerina, etching, with notes, signed, circa 1930s (Box 132)
    - Untitled landscape, watercolor, signed, undated (Box 132)
    - Untitled sketch of three people, pen and watercolor, with notes on the back, signed, 1954 (Box 132)
    - Untitled sketch of seven people, pen, signed, circa 1980's (Box 132)
    - Untitled sketch of a baseball player, pen, signed, 1983 (Box 132)
    - Actor waiting, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Al Linguini, distinguished gangster: "Eat and grow old along with me...", sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Boston at lunch, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Dance from the new platique or "Ballet Beware" twelve sketches, pen and ink wash, signed, bound, 1982 (Box 132)
    - Departmental Buyer, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Editor, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Friends of Liszt, nine sketches, pen, signed, undated (Box 132)
    - A genius as a youth, science went to fast for him, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Give Him Time, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Hyperthyroid Daydream, sketch, pen, signed, undated (Box 132)
    - The I.R.S. man, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Monsignor is offended, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - The New Ring, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - No Way Back From Women's Lib, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - "...Or Else!", sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Overcome by Chopin, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Professor of Literature, New Style, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Re-elected alderman, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Sir Henry Irving, sketch, pencil, with a pencil sketch of a woman on the back, undated (Box 132)
    - Sister knows a secret, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Smearage, sketch, pen, signed, 1983 (Box 132)
    - Teacher Says, That's Enough Now, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Things Things That Americans Put Upon Their Heads, sketches, pencil, annotated, 1955 (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - Thought you had me there, didn't you? sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Too old to be a skeptic, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Tosca, curtain call at the opera, sketch, pen, signed, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Victorian Divine, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - War and Peace, sketch, pen, signed, circa 1950s (Box 132)
    - Weeds- to be adapted for typography, pen, sketch, signed, circa 1930s (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - What diet, sketch, pen, singed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - "What was it?" sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Why Not Me?, sketch, pen, signed, 1979 (Box 132)
    - Edward Nicholas Bookplate, circa 1930s or 1940s (Box 132)
    - A garland of warm sentiments frim Dr. Johnson, reproduction of a print, with notes, undated (Box 132)
    - The Schumann concerto, reproduction of drybrush painting, with notes, circa 1930 (Box 132)
    - Typed note signed to Joseph W. Reed, undated (Box 132)
    - A clipping annotated by Paul Horgan, 1978 (Box 132)
    - List of artwork, 1985 (Box 132)
  - July 1985 Acquisition, 1982-1995, undated
    General
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 326
    - The Annotated Clerihew, typescripts, proofs, 1984; 4 (Box 134)
    - Clerihews: A Gallery, jacket copy, circa 1984 (Box 134)
    - The Clerihews of Paul Horgan, typescripts, notes, manuscripts, copies, proofs, index, 1984-1985; 10 (Box 134)
    - A Gallery of Clerihews, illustrations, typescripts,copies, notes, 1983-1985, undated; 4 (Box 134)
    - Oh Clerihew!, typescript, 1985; 2 (Box 134)
    - Folders, undated (Box 134)
  - July 1985 Acquisition, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 384
    - Notes in relation to the Wesleyan exhibition of his field sketches, holograph, undated (Box 135)
    - [The Horgan House], watercolor and pencil, undated (Box 135)
    - [Kit Reed] watercolor, undated (Box 135)
    - [Paul Horgan] watercolor and pencil, undated (Box 135)
  - July 1985 Acquisition, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA File 100
    - "Contents," typescript, original, and "Insomniac List of Early Movie Stars...," typescript original signed, undated (Box 135)
  - August 1985 Acquisition
    Former call number: Uncat ZA File 98
    - [Clerihew?] proof, annotated, 1985 July 22 (Box 135)
  - September 1985 Acquisition
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 5
    - The Clerihews of Paul Horgan, camera ready copies of galley proofs, 1985 (Box 136)
    - The Clerihews of Paul Horgan, page designs, 1985 (Box 136)
    - The Clerihews of Paul Horgan, master proofs, corrected, 1985 (Box 136)
  - October 1985 Acquisition
    Former call number: Uncat ZA File 102
    - Contract of Paul Horgan with Wesleyan, 1985 (Box 136)
- July 1987 Acquisition, 0.42; (1 box)
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 42
  - Good Friday poems, holograph and typescript, and a publisher's dummy; miscellaneous poems, typescript, and holograph; letters from Robert Giroux, Richard Wilbur, and Lincoln Kirstein; and printed material, 1936-1964; 5 (Box 137)
- 1990 Acquisitions, 19.51; (36 boxes)
  - January 1990 Acquisition, 1917, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 79
    - Life in an Embassy, collection of pencil drawings, sketches, undated (Box 138)
    - Poems 1909-1925 by T.S. Eliot, 1917 (Box 138)
    - "Japanese" flower arrangement, 6 pencil drawings, undated (Box 138)
    - "Art of Japanese Headdress, 7 cards with 6 pencil drawings, undated (Box 138)
    - "Faces at the Races", pencil drawing, undated (Box 138)
    - "Hatsie dear- here is a page of society", undated (Box 138)
  - June 1990 Acquisition, 1920s-1990, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 147
    - Sketches, undated (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - "The Soloist," "The Steel Trap," and other sketches, 1980-1990 (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - Six sketches, circa 1980 (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - "The Athenaeum," 8 sketches, 1980 August (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - Mrs. Vaish, original illustration by Paul Horgan for a discarded short story, 1920s (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - "Tobias & The Angel: The Challenge,", illustration, 1950s (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - "The Bishop of Sancius (Frontispiece in colour)", undated (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - "Rostand at Iowa State," drawing, undated (Box 139 (Oversize))
    - "Greek Drama at Vassar," drawing, undated (Box 139 (Oversize))
  - October 1990 Acquisition, 1933-1990, undated
    Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 385
    - List (Box 140)
    - Notes in Passing, undated (Box 140)
    - Los Angeles Times Book Prize, diploma and related materials, 1987 (Box 140)
    - Project for a Limited Editions Club edition of A Distant Trumpet, 1979 (Box 140)
    - Interview by Robert Gish for Bloomsbury Review, 1988 (Box 140)
    - Encounters with Stravinsky, part 1, undated (Box 140)
    - Encounters with Stravinsky, press notices, reviews, undated (Box 140)
    - Mrs. L., undated (Box 140)
    - Not Even a Footnote, undated (Box 140)
    - Whitewater, contracts and correspondence regarding motion picture contract, undated (Box 140)
    - A Tree on the Plains, undated (Box 140)
    - American Wildcatter, undated (Box 140)
    - A Word for I. J. Griffin Jr., undated (Box 140)
    - North of Mexico, undated (Box 140)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 140)
    - Papers relating to Paul Horgan's membership on the first National Council for the Humanities, undated (Box 140)
    - Wesleyan concerns, 1981 (Box 140)
    - Notes for literary projects (Box 140)
    - Miscellaneous papers and introductions, undated (Box 140)
    - A Writer's Eye, exhibition, undated (Box 141)
    - A Certain Climate, bound proof, 1988 (Box 141)
    - St. David's Night, undated (Box 141)
    - Notes for stories, undated; 3 (Box 141)
    - Proposal to establish a New Mexico Institute of Public Affairs as a four year college, undated (Box 141)
    - Lamy of Santa Fe, reviews and press notices, undated (Box 141)
    - Of America East and wet, notices, reviews, letters, undated (Box 141)
    - A Certain Climate, press notices, reviews, letters, undated (Box 141)
    - A Writer's Eye, reviews and letters (Box 141)
    - Notes on Regionalism, undated (Box 141)
    - The Thin Mountain Air, undated (Box 141)
    - Biography, materials, 1950-1986 (Box 141)
    - Return of the Weed, 1978 (Box 141)
    - Clippings and reviews, undated (Box 142)
    - The Beethoven Society of Roswell, New Mexico, programs, 1935-1954 (Box 142)
    - Novel in Progress, chapter one, 1990 (Box 142)
    - At the Weirs, undated (Box 142)
    - Citizen of New Salem, in the Saturday Evening Post, 1961 March 4 (Box 142)
    - Of the Father and the Son, undated (Box 142)
    - The Affair of the Yzanga Crown Jewels, undated (Box 142)
    - The Faithful and the Unfaithful, undated (Box 142)
    - The Food of Love, undated (Box 142)
    - Forty-Four Brass Buttons, 1990 (Box 142)
    - The Black Guidon: An Episode of the Mexican War, 1990 (Box 142)
    - Motivation of Army Manpower, undated (Box 142)
    - Texas Monthly Press, correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 142)
    - Drawings (Box 142)
    - Brief Lives, undated (Box 143)
    - Caricatures of groups, undated (Box 143)
    - Letters to Paul Horgan of particular interest, 1971-1984 (Box 143)
    - Brother Clementine, undated (Box 143)
    - Correspondence
      - Unsorted letters to Paul Horgan, 1969-1987, undated; 7 (Box 143)
      - Unsorted letters to Paul Horgan, 1969-1987, undated; 10 (Box 144)
      - Unsorted letters to Paul Horgan, 1969-1987, undated (Box 145)
      - Letter to Peter and Henriette Hurd, 1960 May 11 (Box 145)
      - Abney-Crofts, 1935-1987, undated; 113 (Box 146)
      - Crosby-Hersey, 1935-1987, undated; 170 (Box 147)
      - Hertz-Mayer, 1935-1987, undated; 138 (Box 148)
      - Nobokov-Zuidema, 1935-1987, undated; 187 (Box 149)
    - Reviews, 32 (Box 150)
    - Reviews, notices, and scrapbooks
      - Main Line West, 1936 (Box 151 (Oversize))
      - Saintmaker's Christmas Eve, 1957 (Box 152 (Oversize))
      - Unsorted, 1936-1980; 11 (Box 153)
      - Unsorted, undated; 8 (Box 153)
      - No Quarter Given, undated (Box 154 (Oversize))
      - Great River, undated; 3 (Box 155 (Oversize))
      - Great River, undated (Box 160 (Oversize))
      - Centuries of Santa Fe, 1956 (Box 156 (Oversize))
      - The Fault of Angels, 1933; 2 (Box 157 (Oversize))
      - Mexico Bay, 1982; 2 (Box 158)
      - A Lamp on the Plains, unbound sheets for Humble powers, and five published stories, undated; 3 (Box 158)
      - Theatre, undated; 2 (Box 158)
    - Clerihews of Paul Horgan, original manuscript and varients, undated (Box 158)
    - Drawings, undated; 8 (Box 158)
    - Letters from Paul Horgan to the Hurds, 1939-1966; 5 (Box 158)
    - Everything to Live For, clippings, undated (Box 159)
    - Minnie Maddern Fiske, 1930-1937 (Box 159)
    - The Thin Mountain Air, clippings, 1977; 2 (Box 159)
    - Things As They Are, clippings, 1977 (Box 159)
    - Great River, clippings, undated; 2 (Box 161 (Oversize))
    - Humble Powers, clippings, 1955 (Box 162 (Oversize))
    - The Cottonwoods, undated (Box 163)
    - A Woman of Our Day, undated (Box 163)
    - The Pure in Heart, undated; 2 (Box 163)
    - Caleb Varney, undated; 2 (Box 163)
    - Brandywine, undated (Box 163)
    - 43 short stories, original drafts, undated; 5 (Box 164)
    - Forty-Four Brass Buttons (Box 164)
    - Materials relating to autobiography
      - Photographs, undated; 2 (Box 165)
      - Clippings and correspondence, 1977 (Box 165)
      - Printed material, undated (Box 165)
      - Photograph album, undated (Box 165)
      - Family books (Box 165)
      - Address book and The Canadian Review of American Studies, 1971, undated (Box 166)
      - Printed material, correspondence, and photographs, 1940-1981; 4 (Box 166)
      - The Rohr Family Album, 1984 (Box 166)
      - The Bronco, 1941 (Box 166)
    - Printed material and correspondence, 1958-1984; 5 (Box 167)